nufc.co.uk 2019-06-26

# Newcastle United - Official Club Website

icon_corner icon_start_stop enlarge2 icon_start_stop icon_start_stop icon_post icon_miss icon_save icon_card_red enlarge2 icon_save icon_start_stop icon_card_yellow attack icon chevron-down icon chevron-left icon chevron-right icon chevron-up icon cross icon defence icon icon_disallowed_goal email icon facebook icon google icon instagram icon linkedin icon messenger icon pinterest icon play icon plus-thin icon plus icon search icon soundcloud icon sub-in icon sub-out icon icon_sub tweet icon twitter icon icon_user__out icon_user_out vimeo icon whatsapp icon icon_start_stop youtube icon

High Contrast is on. Turn off You can turn high contrast on again via the link in the footer to our accessibilty page

**About us  
** Newcastle United is a group of companies which includes Newcastle United Football Company Limited (together "NUFC", "we" and "us"). For the purposes of the General Data Protection Legislation and any successor legislation, Newcastle United Football Company Limited is the data controller in respect of any personal data provided to or collected by us.

Newcastle United takes the privacy of all its website users very seriously and takes great care to protect your information. This privacy policy explains what information we collect about you, how we may use it, and the steps we take to ensure that it is kept secure. We also explain your rights and how to contact us.

Please note this website contains links to other websites which are provided for your convenience. We are only responsible for the privacy practices and security of this website.

We recommend that you also check the privacy and security policies and procedures of each and every other website that you visit.

You can read our applicant privacy policy here. (PDF download)

**What information do we collect?  
** In order to provide you with services, we may collect personal information about you from our website, telephone conversations, emails and written and verbal communications. We may, for example, keep a record of your name, address, delivery address, email address and telephone number. When you contact us we may also record details of any disability or health needs you may have at the time of booking an event or service which will take place at the stadium or any of our other premises to help to ensure your safety.

We may supplement the information that you provide with other information that we obtain from our dealings with you or which we receive from other organisations, for example, our commercial partners.

**How will we use your information? And our lawful bases  
** All personal information that we obtain about you will be recorded, used, and protected by us in accordance with current data protection legislation and this privacy policy. We will primarily use your personal information to provide our products and services to you and, for example:  

**Purpose**    |    **Lawful basis**  
---|---  
to communicate with you about the services and / or products you have requested | Performance of a contract. If you do not provide us with the information we need to perform our contract with you then we may need to terminate the contract.  
to communicate with you in the event that any products or services you have requested are unavailable | Performance of a contract. If you do not provide us with the information we need to perform our contract with you then we may need to terminate the contract.  
to respond to any enquiries you make | Legitimate interests – that we need to assist you with the enquiry you have made  
to provide you with information about our offers which may be of interest to you (where you have provided us with consent to do so) | Consent  
to provide you with offers from our commercial partners (a list of which can be found [here](https://www.nufc.co.uk/club/partners/current-partners) (where you have provided us with consent to do so) | Consent  
for record keeping purposes - to improve the quality of our service | This will be done on an anonymized basis  
for market research | This will be done on an anonymized basis  
to track activity on our website | This will be done on an anonymized basis  
  
You should be aware that if we are requested by the police or any other regulatory or government authority investigating suspected illegal activities to provide your personal details and/or information concerning your activities whilst visiting the website, we may do so if we are obliged by law.

**How long will we keep your information?  
** Where you have not registered with us and/or you have no Supporter ID number, we will keep your information in line with the timescales set out below:

**Type of Information**   | **When will it be deleted**  
---|---  
Contact details (for products / services) | 6 years after the contract has been satisfied  
Contact details (to deal with an enquiry only) | 6 months after we have finished dealing with your enquiry  
Contact details (where you have provided your consent to be contacted about offers) | For such time as you have provided us with consent to do so. Please note if we do not hear from you within a period of 12 months, we will get in touch to see if you still want to hear from us.   
  
**  
Disclosure of your information to service providers**  
In order to provide our products and services to you, we may need to appoint other organisations to carry out some of the processing activities on our behalf. These will include, for example, delivery organisations and mailing houses. In these circumstances, we will ensure that your information is properly protected and that it is only used in accordance with this policy. We will also make sure that we have appropriate contracts in place with these third parties.

**Offers and opportunities  
** Newcastle United teams up with a selection of carefully chosen commercial partners, an up-to-date list of our commercial partners is available by [clicking here](https://www.nufc.co.uk/club/partners/current-partners).

Our commercial partner programme is designed to support the Club and also to bring customers, fans and website users a diverse range of opportunities and offers (including financial services offers) at competitive prices. Newcastle United and/or these commercial partners would like to contact you with details of offers in a number of ways, including post, telephone, text/picture/video message, digital television, fax or by email. Where you have provided us with consent to do so and you express an interest in an offer from one of our commercial partners, that partner may let us know. This enables us to take your views and interests into account when choosing our commercial partners and developing the programme.

**What to do if you do not want to receive details of offers  
** Please be assured, we will only contact you with details of offers if you have provided us with express consent to do so. You can also change your mind at any time and withdraw consent.

Please note, if you do withdraw your consent to receive information, we and/or our commercial partners will be unable to keep you informed of new services, products, events or special offers that may interest you and our ability to inform you of ticketing opportunities will be affected.

**Use of your information outside the European Union  
** Some of the organisations to which we may disclose your personal information are situated outside of the European Union. In order to provide you with the products and services you require, we may need to transfer your personal information to these countries and we will always ensure that the appropriate safeguards are in place.

**Policy for children  
** We understand that children will visit our website or interact with our content. We encourage all persons under 13 to consult with their parents or legal guardian before interacting with our content or submitting information to us. Parents or legal guardians should supervise children when online.

If you are under the age of 18, you may still participate in competitions and promotions. However, notification of a win, offer or prize should be sent directly to your parent or legal guardian. The contact details of your parent or guardian should therefore be provided in the initial registration process. Any publication of a competition winner’s personal details for visitors known to us to be under 18 will require parental or legal guardian consent during registration.

**Cookies  
** We use cookies in order to ensure the website functions properly and to improve your user experience. Cookies are usually a string of numbers and/or letters that a website transfers to your hard drive. The cookies enable the website to "remember" you, either for the duration of your visit (session cookies) or for repeat visits (persistent cookies). We recommend that you visit the websites [www.allaboutcookies.org](http://www.allaboutcookies.org/) and [www.cookiecentral.com ](http://www.cookiecentral.com/)if you would like in-depth information about cookies.

  | Description   
---|---  
Strictly necessary cookies | These cookies are essential to enable you to navigate around the website securely and to provide you with services you have specifically requested. For instance, they help ensure that payments are processed securely.  
Functionality cookies | These cookies enhance the functionality of the website by storing your preferences. For instance, they can remember your name and location, if you provide this information.  
Performance cookies | These cookies improve the performance of the website. For instance, they help pages load quicker.  
Online behavioural cookies | These cookies store information about your behaviour online, such as your browsing history. For instance, they help us tailor the advertising we show to you to your interests.  
  
Most web browsers automatically accept cookies, but if you prefer, you can change your browser to prevent that. You are not obliged to accept cookies and you can adjust your browser's setting to prevent it from accepting cookies on your computer - go to [www.cookiecentral.com](http://www.cookiecentral.com/) for instructions on how to disable cookies. However, you may not be able to take full advantage of our website or use certain functions if you disable cookies. If you continue to use our website, you agree to our use of cookies.

**Security of information  
** We take the security of your personal information seriously. When you submit your credit card details, we use industry standard Secure Sockets Layer (SSL) encryption technology to guard your information. In addition, we have security procedures in place to protect our paper based systems and computerised databases from loss and misuse, and only allow access to them when it is absolutely necessary to do so, and then under strict guidelines as to what use may be made of the personal information contained within them. Please note that we cannot guarantee any data transmission over the internet is completely secure.

**Monitoring  
** We may monitor or record telephone calls for security purposes and to improve the quality of services that we provide to you. We will always inform you if we are recording a call.

**Changes to this privacy policy  
** We aim to meet high standards and our policies and procedures are, therefore, constantly under review. From time to time we may change our security and privacy policies. If and when we have update this policy, we will place an alert on our website so that you can see what has changed.

**Your rights  
** You have the following rights in relation to data protection:

  1. The right to access your personal information
  2. The right to have your information updated
  3. The right (in certain circumstances) to have your information deleted
  4. The right to object to or restrict processing of your information
  5. The right to data portability
  6. The right to withdraw your consent at any time
  7. The right to complain to the Information Commissioner’s Office 

If you would like to exercise any of your rights with us then please contact us using the contact details set out below.

**  
****How to contact us  
** If you would like any further information or have any comments about our privacy policy or any other aspect of our website or service, please contact our Data Protection Lead by any of the methods shown below:

 **Telephone:** 0844 372 1892  
**Email:** dataprotection@nufc.co.uk     
**Mail:** Data Protection Lead

Newcastle United Football Club  
St. James' Park  
Newcastle upon Tyne  
NE1 4ST
